# Jeff Hoffman

## Data Science, Engineering, & Innovation Professional

Address Turlock, CA, 95382 Phone (209) 602-2437 E-mail mrjeffhoffman@gmail.com LinkedIn <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mrieffhoffman/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/mrieffhoffman/</a>

Data Scientist familiar with gathering, cleaning and organizing data for use by technical and non-technical personnel. Advanced understanding of statistical, algebraic and other analytical techniques. Highly organized, motivated and diligent with significant background in Mechanical Engineering & Project Management. 10 years professional work experience with a passion for exploring, learning, and applying data science using Python, Pandas, SQL, Machine Learning, and EDA.

### **Projects**

- <u>Driven Data Flu Shot Learning Competition GitHub</u> (machine learning)
- <u>Certification Case Study Used Car Sales DataCamp</u> (EDA, machine learning)
- High Fatality Accidents Competition DataCamp (EDA, machine learning)
- <u>Lego Data Analysis Python Notebook</u> (SQL, Pandas data manipulation)

## **Education & Certifications**

#### 2021 - 2021 Data Science Professional

DataCamp - Certificate

#### 2017 - 2020 MBA: Innovation Management

University of Colorado At Colorado Springs - Colorado Springs, CO

• Relevant Coursework Completed: Project Management, Operations Management, Finance, Accounting & Leadership

#### 2004 - 2010

## Bachelor of Science: Mechanical Engineering, Business Administration

California State University - Chico - Chico, CA

- Member of Chico State Water-ski Team
- Elected to President, Treasurer for Chico State Water-ski in 2008 2010

#### Work History

#### **2021 - Current**

## **Mechanical Project Engineer**

CertainTeed Insulation Group, Chowchilla, CA

- Planned, managed, and implemented complex mechanical projects up to \$500k.
- Effectively manage and **facilitate change** by interfacing with multiple departments and key people.
- Managed up to 10 projects at once.

#### 2019 - 2020

## **Design Engineer**

Flory Industries, Salida, CA

- Responsible for design work and delivery of **complex mechanical projects.**
- Utilized group **project management tools** for addressing over 100 action items per week.
- Planned goals and schedules and prepared presentation materials.

#### 2012 - 2019

## **Product Engineer**

Parker Hannifin, Modesto, CA

- Responsible for managing a diverse fuel filtration product line
  - o \$81.5M in annual sales and 339 unique customers.
- **Communicated technical aspects** of projects to cross-functional teams.
- Interfaced with project stakeholders to develop value-added product requirements.
- Increased new release efficiency by reducing project completion time by 14 days.